Mss.B.V462
American Philosophical Society
- Series I: Correspondence, 1768-1922; c. 850 items.
  - Certification in re John Vaughan, Jan. 5, 1782; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Birmingham, Copy of D. On same sheet with copy of letter from B. Franklin to R. Morris; Jan. 19, 1782. ---- For another copy of this see in letter from Sam. Vaughan to John Vaughan, March 4, 1782. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Certification in re John Vaughan, Jan. 10, 1782; Price, Richard, 1723-1791
    Newington Green, Copy of D. On same sheet with copy of letter from B. Franklin to R. Morris; ---- For another copy of this see in letter from Sam. Vaughan to John Vaughan, March 4, 1782. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Mr. and Mrs. Bache, Jan. 19, 1782; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Copy of D. Introducing John Vaughan. On same sheet with copy of letter from B. Franklin to R. Morris; Jan. 19, 1782. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Robt. Morris, Feb. 5, 1782; Jay, John, 1745-1829
    Madrid, Copy of L. On same sheet with copy of letter from B. Franklin to R. Morris; Jan. 19, 1782. Introduces John Vaughan. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 5, 1782; 7 1/2" x 9"; Jay, John, 1745-1829
    Madrid, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Sends him packet which he is to sink in case of danger. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 18, 1782; Franklin, William Temple, 1760-1823
    Passy, Copy of L. On same sheet with copy of letter from B. Franklin to R. Morris; Jan. 19, 1782. In re Mr. Vaughan's intention to go to America. FILM54-58 FRAME 116 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 4, 1782; 7 1/4" x 9"; Vaughan, Samuel, 1720-1802
    London, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Asylum for the Vaughan family in America. Transcribes testimonials from Joseph Priestley, Jan. 5, 1782, and Richard Price, Jan. 10,1782. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to W[illia]m Bingham, March 5, 1782; Harrison, Richard
    Cadiz, Copy of L. On same sheet with copy of letter from B. Franklin to R. Morris; Jan. 19, 1782. Introduces John Vaughan. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Craig, March 5, 1782; Harrison, Richard
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 25, 1782; 7 1/2" x 9"; Morris, Robert, 1734-1806
    Philadelphia, L.S. 4p. Purchase of land in America by the Vaughan family. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Sept. 14, 1782; 7 1/4" x 9"; Cuninghame, P.
    Bordeaux, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. (The end. spells the writer's name: P. Cunningham) Encloses letter to George Nixon. News of the Vaughan family. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to M. Del Campo, Nov. 3, 1782; Jay, John, 1745-1829
    Madrid, Copy of L. On same sheet with copy of letter from B. Franklin to R. Morris; Jan. 19, 1782. In re oath of allegiance to the U.S. to be taken by [John Vaughan ?]. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Dec. 21, 1782; 7 1/4" x 9"; Franklin, William Temple, 1760-1823
    Passy, A.L.S. 3p. and end. His grandfather [B. Franklin] is getting better. Glad Mr. Vaughan is well pleased with America. FILM54-58 FRAME 117 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, Feb. 15, 1783; 7" x 9"; Jay, John, 1745-1829
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and end. The peace; the treaty of commerce. Pennsylvania politics; Mr. Dickinson. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
    General note
    Not located 5/2010.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], March 10, 1783; Pine, Robert Edge, 1730?-1788
    London, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 24, 1783; 6 1/2" x 8"; Jay, John, 1745-1829
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Awaits news from America. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 30, 1783; 7 1/2" x 9"; Morris, Robert, 1734-1806
    Philadelphia, L.S. 1p. and end., also pencil note in re text of letter. [Relative to Vaughan's mission to Holland for the purpose of raising a loan for America ?] MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Rob. Morris, June 2, 1783; 7 1/4" x 9"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    London, A.L.S. 4p. Reasons for failure of scheme. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 3, 1783; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Passy, A.L.S. Thanks him for packet and letters, but wonders why none were dated post Jan.13. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, June 5, 1783; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Walker, George, 1734?-1807
    Nottingham, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Introduces Mr. and Mrs. Sorley. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John [Vaughan], Aug. 12, 1784; 8" x 13"; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1757-1839
    London, A.L. 8p. Business and financial advice. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Copies of letters from 1784, Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 26, 1786; 8" x 13"; Jay, John, 1745-1829
    New York, L.S. 2p. and add., end. New edition of Jay's correspondence with Littlepage. Livingston dispute. Vaughan's mission to Madrid in 1782. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Messrs. Ross & Vaughan, Feb. 8, 1786; 8" x 13"; Jay, John, 1745-1829
    New York, L.S. 1p. and add., end. Acknowledges notification of arrival of glass and other merchandise from Havre. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 8, 1786; 6 1/4" x 7 3/4"; Livingston, Henry Brookholst, 1757-1823.
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Relative to facts about John Jay in Madrid [see Jay's letters to J.V., Jan. 26, 1786]. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Messrs. Ross & Vaughan, Aug. 17, 1786; 6 1/4" x 7 3/4"; Rutledge, John, 1739-1800
    Charleston, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Business. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 3, 1787; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Business. Mentions Dr. Franklin. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Messrs. Ross and Vaughan, June 22, 1787; 6 3/4" x 8 3/4"; Barbançon, comte de
    A.L.S. 4p. In French Orders plants from America. Mentions [W.T.] Franklin. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 13, 1787; 8" x 10 1/2"; Laurens, Henry, 1724-1792
    Mepkin plantation, So. Carolina, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Financial transactions. Federal convention. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 1, 1787; 7 1/2" x 9"; Jay, John, 1745-1829
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. "Advisable for the people of America to adopt the constitution proposed by the late convention." MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 8, 1787; 6 1/4" x 7 3/4"; Rutledge, John, 1739-1800
    Charleston, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Business. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John and Samuel Vaughan, Dec. 26, 1787; 6 1/2" x 8"; Vaughan, Samuel, 1720-1802
    Fort Penn, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Recommends planting of trees for the Philosophical building and the Academy. Mentions Dr. Franklin. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 27, 1788; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Washington, George, 1732-1799
    Mount Vernon, Copy of L. 1p. Acknowledges receipt of work by Fabius. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 27, 1788; Jay, John, 1745-1829
    Poughkeepsie, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Certain issue involving Dr. Franklin. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 4, 1788; 7 1/4" x 9"; Burr, Aaron, 1756-1836
    N. York, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Encloses two letters for Major Prevost. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 4, 1788; 7 1/4" x 9"; Burr, Aaron, 1756-1836
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 10, 1789; 8 1/4" x 13 1/6"; Livingston, Brockholst, 1757-1823
    New York, 1 p. address and endorsement. A.L.S. Orders 20,000 bricks with which to build his house. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Certificate of membership issued to John Vaughan, April 23, 1789; 11 1/2" x 9 1/4"; Society of the Sons of St. George
    Printed from S: Robt. Morris, president; Wm. Rawle (?), treasurer; Asheton Humphreys, secretary. 1p. Seal. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 11, 1789; 8" x 12"; Vaughan, Samuel, 1720-1802
    Jamaica, 1 p. address and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends six bottles of castor oil, some oil, orange, lime, and chadock plants to John Vaughan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 23, 1789; 7 1/2" x 9"; Laurens, Henry, 1724-1792
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. L. Unsigned. Copy. Extract only. Regarding experiments upon the cultivation of different varieties of rice. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Samuel Vaughan, jr., Sept. 2, 1789; 7 1/4" x 9 1/4"; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1757-1839
    London, A.L.S. 4p., add. European and American politics. Dr. Herschel's progress on his telescope. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Jasper Yeates, Lancaster, Feb. 27, 1790; 9x7-1/2; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning a deed from Kearn to Whitmore. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], March 31, 1791; Pinckney, Thomas, 1750-1828
    Charleston, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Jonathan Williams, May 10, 1791; 7" x 8 3/4"; Ingenhousz, Jan, 1730-1799
    "In Mr. Franklin's lodging," London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Business transaction with Mr. Wharton. Mentions Dr. Franklin. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 27, 1791; 4 1/2" x 7 1/2"; Washington, George, 1732-1799
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Laments revolt among the blacks. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, May 24, 1792; 7 1/2" x 9"; Monroe, James, 1758-1831
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Relative to Mr. Hopkins' demand. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Murray and J. Vaughan, May 26, 1792; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Genet, Edmond Charles, 1763-1834
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Aug. 13, 1792; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add. and end. Asks Mr. Vaughan to act as agent for goods for M. de Rieux. FILM 199 FRAME 254 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 18, 1793; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Jay, John, 1745-1829
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Acknowledges work from Benjamin Vaughan transmitted by Mr. Jefferson. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 8, 1793; 8" x 10"; Hamilton, Alexander, 1757-1804
    Treasury dept., L.S. 1p. and add., end. Drafts drawn by M. Genet. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, July 21, 1793; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.L. in 3d P. 1p., add. On the reverse is a bill drawn against the estate of James Wilson by Jesse and Rob. Waln. Financial transactions. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], July 23, 1793; Izard, Ralph, 1742-1804
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 25, 1793; Izard, Ralph, 1742-1804
    Boston, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Transfer of one share of stock of the Bank of the U.S. to John Vaughan, Oct. 26, 1793; Tudor, William
    [Boston] Photostat of printed D. filled in in ms. and S. 1p. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 20, 1794; 7 3/4" x 10"; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1757-1839
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Introduces M. de Talleyrand Perigord. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John [Vaughan], Feb. 27, 1794; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1757-1839
    London, A.L.S. 4p. Introduces Messrs. Talleyrand-Perigord and Beaumetz. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 8, 1794; 8 1/8" x 12 5/8"; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    New York, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Political views of Dr. Priestley. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 1794; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Vaughan, William
    London, 2 pp. and endorsement. L. Unsigned. Copy. Regarding the alleged execution of an American, Mr. Smith, in Venice. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Statement that he has imported 250 pipes of brandy, July 3, 1794; 6-1/4x9-1/2; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, A.D.S. 1p. (see John Vaughan papers.) Formerly B V462.2. Purchased from Fleming; Aug. 22, 1962. Access. No.: 1962 1362a.ms.
  - Letter to Messrs. Dallarde Swan & Co., July 10, 1794; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Contains also letter of July 12, 1794. Relative to Joseph Priestley's affairs. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Messrs. Dallarde Swan & Co., July 12, 1794; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. "copy" On same sheet with letter of July 10,1794. Business letter. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 8, 1794; 8" x 13"; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Northumberland, A.L.S. 4p., add., end. Recollection of a conversation relative to a French invasion of England. Household goods. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 20 (?), 1795; 8" x 10"; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Northumberland, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Recollection of a conversation relative to the possibility of an invasion of England by France. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 26, 1795; 8" x 12 3/4"; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Northumberland, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In re conversation about French invasion of England. Plan of a college in Northumberland. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Phila., Feb. 17, 1795; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    North., Photostat of A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Legal matters. Presented by Dr. Eugene F. DuBois, through Dr. L.P. Eisenhart, June 1957. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Order to John Vaughan to deduct his subscription to the Northumberland academy from interest due on Mr. Priestley's bond, March 31, 1795; 6 1/2" x 6 3/4"; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813
    A.D. 1p. and add., end. Pasted to this is Rush signature clipped from another document. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, May 3, 1795; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; La Rochefoucauld-Liancourt, François-Alexandre-Frédéric, duc de, 1747-1827
    Philadelphia, A.L. in 3d P. 1p. and end. In French. Financial transactions. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to De La Motte & Co., June 27, 1795
    Recommends Mr. Humphries. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 29, Sept. 11, 1795; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1757-1839
    Basle, A.L. 3p. and add. Finances. European politics. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Oct. 8, 1795; 7 1/2" x 9"; Talleyrand-Périgord, Charles Maurice de, prince de Bénévent, 1754-1838
    A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 12, [1795]; 8" x 10"; Talleyrand-Périgord, Charles Maurice de, prince de Bénévent, 1754-1838
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 17, 1795; 7 1/2" x 8 3/4"; Talleyrand-Périgord, Charles Maurice de, prince de Bénévent, 1754-1838
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. In French. Financial transactions. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 21, 1796; 8" x 10"; Thomson, Charles, 1729-1824
    Harriton, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Translation of the Old and New Testaments. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], April 7, 1796; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Thomson, Charles, 1729-1824
    Harriton, A.L.S. 6p. Acknowledges specimen of Mr. Geddes' translation [of the Bibel]; sends specimen of his own translation from the Septuagint. Contains note by John Vaughan and news clippings about Thomson; presented by Mr. vaughan, Sept. 1835. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Messr. LeRoy, Bayard & McEvers; and reply, April 26 and 27, 1796; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Concerning payment. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 31, 1797; 8" x 10"; Jay, John, 1745-1829
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Acknowledges engraving of Washington after Stuart portrait. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 2, 1797; 8" x 10"; Jay, John, 1745-1829
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Sends report of the Committee of the Lords and Commons. News of Vaughan's family. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Deposition about a tract of land in Bedford co., March 23, 1798; 8 1/2" x 10 1/4"; Smith, William, 1727-1803
    A.D.S. 1p. Mentions William Peters and George Croghan. Contains other ms. notes. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Note relative to the reaction of Dr. George Logan to taking the census of 1790, 1791, March 29, 1798
    MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 20, 1798; 7 1/2" x 9"; Louis Philippe, King of the French, 1773-1850
    Trenton, A.L.S: D'Orleans. 1p. and add., end. In French. Accompanying this is a pen once owned by the king, with an account of its provenance by Jacob Snider, dated Phila., Dec.22,1851. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Account of his estate, Aug. 31, 1798; 7 1/2" x 12 1/2"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    real and personal A.D. 2p. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], Nov. 3, 1798; 7 1/4" x 9"; Louis Philippe, King of the French, 1773-1850
    Trenton, A.L.S: D'Orleans... 1p. In French. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to (John Vaughan?), July 22, 1799; 7" x 9 1/4"; Shirley, Henry
    Kingston, Jamaica, 1 p. A.L.S. Forwards power of attorney. Personal affairs. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 13, 1800; 8-1/4x6-1/2; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Northumberland, Xerox of A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. Financial affairs. Quotes Franklin. Refers to Benjamin Vaughan. Foreign news. Presented by Charles W. Mann; July 1, 1969. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, Jan. 10, 1801; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Wilmington, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p. Bur. of rolls, v.8,547 - Ser.2,v.83,73. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 27, 1801; 7 5/8" x 9 7/8"; Barton, William, 1754-1817
    Lancaster, 4 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Cannot reply to Mr. Jaudenes' letters due to his political position as complicated by Franco-American relations. Asks Mr. Vaughan to explain this to Mr. Jaudenes. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Enoch Edwards, April 10, 1801; 7 1/2" x 9 1/4"; Ségur, Louis-Philippe, comte de, 1753-1830
    Paris, 20 germinal an 9. A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 7, 1801; 8" x 9 5/8"; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Northumberland, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Improved health of his daughter. Mr. Antes nearly cured of the stone. Hopes books have arrived from England, which should be forwarded to him as quickly as possible. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], May 19, 1801; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. Bur. of rolls, v.10,189 - Ser.6,v.7,17. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 4, 1801; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Northumberland, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Troubles of his son. Encloses draught for $300 out of the $400 that Vaughan advanced to his son. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION
  - Letter to Thos. Jefferson, June 24, 1801; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Wilmington, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p. Bur, of rolls, v.10,190 - Ser.6,v.7,32. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, July 13, 1801; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Wilmington, Photostat of A.L.S. 4p. Bur. of rolls, v.8,547 - Ser.2,v.83,74. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, July 28, 1801; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Wilmington, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. Bur. of rolls, v.8,547 - Ser.2,v.83,75. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 7, 1801; 7 7/8" x 9 1/2"; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Northumberland, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests Mr. Vaughan to procure him an ounce of silver and half an ounce of gold. Asks that parcel of books from Mr. Johnson be forwarded. Vicinity of Northumberland "uncommonly sickly." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], Oct. 10, 1801; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Wilmington, Photostat of A.L.S. 3p. Bur. of rolls, v.8,547 - Ser.2,v.83,76. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Thos. Jefferson, Oct. 22, 1801; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p. Bur. of rolls, v.8,547 - Ser.2,v.83,80. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Nov. 5, 1801; 8" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Observations on inoculation for smallpox. Bur. of rolls, v.6,470 - Ser. 1,v.8,234. FILM 199 FRAME 256 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, Nov. 10, 1801; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p. Bur. of rolls, v.8,547 - Ser.2,v.83,81. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Nov. 10, 1801; Photocopy; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Asks about books he requested from London. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, Nov. 19, 1801; 7 3/4" x 10"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia Letterpress copy of A.L.S. 2p. Inoculation; Drs. Coxe, Rush and others. Mr. Peale and the skeleton of the mammoth. Additions to APS library from Dr. Franklin's and Mr. Bird's (sic) libraries. FILM 199 FRAME 276 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to T. Jefferson, Nov. 20, 1801; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. Bur. of rolls,v.8,547 - Ser.2,v.83,83. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Nov. 24, 1801; 8" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Inoculation for smallpox. Bur. of rolls, v.6,470 - Ser. 1,v.8, 245. FILM 199 FRAME 257 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, Dec. 9, 1801; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. Bur. of rolls, v.10,190 - Ser.6,v.7,80. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 10, 1801; 7 1/2" x 9 1/8"; Crawford, John
    Baltimore, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Desires "to promote vaccination in this city". Experiments therewith. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], Dec. 21, 1801; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. Bur. of rolls, v.10,190 - Ser.6,v.7,83. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, Dec. 29, 1801; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p. and enc. - 1p. Bur. of rolls, v.8,547 - Ser. 2,v.83,84. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Miscellaneous notes on vaccination, 1801; 8" x 13 1/2"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.D. 3p. and end. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 17, 1802; 8 1/8" x 9 1/2"; Stewart, John
    Golden Square, London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding a book of his "embracing the Interests of all Mankind." Wishes Mr. Vaughan to assist him in selling it. Prospectus enclosed. MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 27, 1802; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Du Pont de Nemours
    New York, 1 p. address and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Paid Lowell $2,200 to secure township. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, May 8, 1802; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Photostat of A.L.S. 4p. Bur. of rolls, v.8,547 - Ser.2,v.83,86. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 25, 1802; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Northumberland, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends a few copies of proposal for two of his projected publications, to be distributed among his friends. Rejoiced at the prospect of peace. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, June 8, 1802; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Photostat of A.L.S. 6p. Bur. of rolls, v.8,547 - Ser. 2,v.83,87. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION